<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Posts on SquareCows</title>
    <link>/posts/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Posts on SquareCows</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Thu, 02 Feb 2023 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="/posts/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Case Study: Freewebstore.com</title>
      <link>/posts/case-study-freewebstore/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 02 Feb 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/posts/case-study-freewebstore/</guid>
      <description>Case Study: Freewebstore About Freewebstore Freewebstore is the world&amp;rsquo;s largest free eCommerce platform, allowing 7000+ customers access to selling their goods online. Formed in 2008, the business has grown from the data centre into the cloud and uses AWS exclusively. The company operates from its HQ in Burnley, Lancashire, UK.
Challenges: Cost Optimization with no performance degradation Freewebstore is a small but advanced user of AWS. They consume many AWS products and need to drive down monthly costs without affecting performance.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Enable Cost and Usage Reports (CUR)</title>
      <link>/posts/enable-curs/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 31 Jan 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/posts/enable-curs/</guid>
      <description>Why choose CUR? In order to analyse your AWS billing in detail you need to switch on Cost and Usage Reporting (CUR). This allows you to see a very fine grained report on your billing data, from on-demand costs to how much of your RI or savings plan is being used. When working with SquareCows we&amp;rsquo;ll ask you to enable this and run the data for at least 30 days in order to cacth month begining and end, which should give us a good idea of your standard usage of AWS and make more informed cost savings calculations.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Migrating disks from GP2 to GP3</title>
      <link>/posts/gp3-disks/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 05 Oct 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/posts/gp3-disks/</guid>
      <description>Migrating from GP2 disks to GP3 to Save Money on Your AWS Bill GP3 disks were announced back in December 2020 as a new and improved standard disk which promised the potential of 20% savings over the GP2 disks. Despite this, I rarely see a customer who&amp;rsquo;s migrated their disks from GP2 to GP3, so here is a blog post that should get you started and on your way.
Why GP3?</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
